Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/yen-nguyen-thi-hoang-7a0151b4 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Lean Six Sigma Team Leadership Manufacturing

Yen Nguyen Thi Hoang

Technical Project Manager - Fortescue Hydrogen Systems Vietnam

Summary

Experienced Planning and Project Manager with a demonstrated history of working in manufacturing. Skilled in Strategic Planning, Supply Chain Management, Manufacturing, Project Management, and Team Leadership.

MBA graduated from Solvay Brussels School - National Economics University, Hanoi.

PMP and Lean Six Sigma Green Belt certified.

Experience

Fortescue

Technical Project Manager June 2024 - Present (10 months)

Perth, Western Australia, Australia

KPMG Vietnam

Associated Director - Customer & Operations, Management Consulting March 2021 - June 2024 (3 years 4 months)

VINFAST LLC

Program Management Officer December 2019 - March 2021 (1 year 4 months) Hanoi

ABB

9 years 4 months

Planning Manager - Power Transformer January 2018 - June 2019 (1 year 6 months)

Hanoi, Vietnam

Overall monitoring master planning and production planning of 2 factories for small power transformers and distribution transformers, total revenue target is about \$80mio.

Planning and Warehouse Manager - SPT factory

Page 1 of 3

January 2015 - December 2017 (3 years)

Hanoi, Vietnam

- Master planner for transformer factory with revenue target \$50mio annually, possibly expanding to \$65 mio in 2020.
- Following up important KPIs of factory: Revenue, Productivity, Overtime reduction.
- Proactively involving in supply chain activity to ensure on time delivery of materials.
- Workload calculation for backlog and tendering orders for labor resource arrangement and preparation.
- Providing budget of working hours for Sales & Controller for cost calculation for product types.
- Warehouse management supplying all necessary materials and components to factory in an area of 1000m2 and store appx. 5000 material codes as stock.
- An inspiring and high demanding leader of the 11 team members.
- A member of ABB Operational Excellence Program.
- · Skillful at SAP PP, PS, MM Module

Planning Officer

May 2014 - December 2014 (8 months)

Hanoi, Vietnam

- Set up and control factory Master plan based on order backlog and order forecast.
- Set up project's milestones based on input from Master plan, material lead time. Monitor weekly project status. Update and follow up with functional departments to maintain Master plan.
- Monitor order report to remark materials shortage, critical point, control point
 of the critical process before production starts. Send the signal to relevant
 departments to start production as scheduled.
- Follow up with production department to solve problem appearing during production time and keep FAT date as scheduled.
- Prepare report of load forecasted in the workshop and recommend solutions.
- Skillful in SAP PP, MM Module

Project Manager

March 2010 - May 2014 (4 years 3 months)

Hanoi, Vietnam

 In charge of project monitoring from contract hand over until delivery in the field of transformer manufacturing, including technical and commercial activities and collaboration between related functional departments assigned as project team members.

- Single contact point to solve issues among customer and factory during execution.
- Handle high-complexity and critical projects with demanding EPC customers:
 Japan, Australia, New Zealand. Highest project revenue ever handled is about USD 5 mio for a 3-year contract.
- Enthusiastic, high energy, trustworthy team player
- ABB Certified Associated Project Manager 2013-2016

Education

Solvay Brussels School - National Economics University, Hanoi Master of Business Administration - MBA · (2016 - 2018)

Hanoi University of Science and Technology
Bachelor's degree, Electrical Engineering - Power System · (2004 - 2009)